<Document>
  # Vox

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobVox" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Warning! This species is not recommended for new players due to their fatal allergy to oxygen![/color]

  Vox breathe nitrogen, and [color=#ffa500]oxygen is toxic to them.[/color]
  Unfortunately, space stations tend to be full of oxygen,
  so Vox must use an internal nitrogen supply at almost all times to avoid fatal exposure.

  Vox always spawn wearing working nitrogen internals equipment.
  A spare breathing mask and an emergency nitrogen canister is provided in their survival box.

  Vox [color=#1e90ff]slowly recover from low levels of poison damage[/color] on their own,
  so long as they are careful not to exceed 20 poison damage.
  This allows them to endure breathing station air for up to thirty seconds at a time without lasting damage,
  letting them quickly eat, drink, take oral medication, and so on.
  A thirty second oxygen exposure takes them two minutes to recover from.
  If their health does not seem to improve within a minute of oxygen exposure, they should seek medical attention.
  They also [color=#1e90ff]slowly recover from low levels of radiation damage[/color].

  Vox deal [color=red]Slash[/color] damage with their unarmed attack.

  Their talons can [color=#1e90ff]grip onto to surfaces[/color], so they don't float off in zero-gravity, but only so long as they [color=#1e90ff]don't wear restrictive footwear[/color]

  They are [color=#ffa500]uncloneable[/color], and so must be extra careful not to come to too much harm.


  [color=#ffd700]Lore:[/color]

  The Vox are an artificially created species that inhabit colossal moon-sized vessels known as arkships or arks,
  scattered across the remote fringes of the Orion Sector's outer rim. The species features several sub-races that live and work alongside each other,
  the most common of which being the Vox Primalis, which serve as laborers and comprise the vast majority of the species. Primalis are ingrained in a rigid caste system from birth,
  a structure overseen by the superior races of Vox Armalis and higher-ranking Primalis, who function as both fanatic zealots and guardians of their respective arks.
  The ark's governance revolves around a theocratic system venerating the Vox Auralis, a small collection of "True Vox", whose path to ascension is dogmatically followed and taught to all Vox,
  to engrain their role in the larger purpose and preservation directed by their god.

  Despite their complex society and impressive technology, Voxkind exerts minimal influence in the sector, primarily due to their arkships' strategic distance from core worlds,
  a deliberate choice to avoid interactions with other species. Despite this distance, Vox individuals are occasionally encountered outside their arks, often as exiles, traders, wanderers,
  or raiders performing assignments for their ark. Their rarity and secretive disposition have unfortunately led to widespread mistrust and prejudice against the Vox by other species,
  fueled by historical incidents and governmental biases, alongside far more justified wariness of the arks themselves, mostly based upon the stories of the uncommon Primalis who are able to truly escape.

  While Vox society may appear monolithic from the outside, in truth it is anything but, with internal strife rampant across Voxkind.
  Arkships often engage in covert assaults or sabotage missions against each other, driven by the zealots under faith to their respective Auralis,
  who are more than willing to declare holy wars over even the smallest of philosophical differences. Even the individual arkships themselves are not strangers to internal conflict,
  with the populace frequently clashing due to the oppressive caste system they work in, and the brutally totalitarian system inherent to all arks.

  As the Arks are highly insular and xenophobic societies, specific information regarding Arkship life, Vox subspecies, and Ark society as a whole is largely unknown to the average non-vox.
  Most people are unlikely to possess this knowledge unless a Vox has explained it to them.
  - Paradise Wiki
</Document>
